https://www.snapcare.co.uk/case-managers-solicitors/snap-privacy-policy.aspx

After your Snap Interview
Create the best CV!
Introduction
This Privacy Policy explains what we do with your personal data, whether we are in the process of helping you find a job, continuing our relationship with you once we have found you a role, providing you with a service, receiving a service from you, using your data to ask for your assistance in relation to one of our Candidates, or you are visiting our website.
It describes how we collect, use and process your personal data and how we comply with our legal obligations to you. Your privacy is important to us, and we are committed to protecting and safeguarding your data privacy rights.
This Privacy Policy applies to the personal data of our website users, candidates, clients, suppliers, referees we may contact or emergency contacts.
For the purpose of applicable data protection legislation (including but not limited to the General Data Protection Regulation (the "GDPR"), the company responsible for your personal data ("Snap Care" or "us") can be found here.
It is important to point out that we may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Please just visit this page if you want to stay up to date.
If you are dissatisfied with any aspect of our Privacy Policy, you may have legal rights and where relevant, we have described these as well.
This Privacy Policy applies in relevant countries throughout our international network. Different countries may approach data privacy in different ways and we will make adjust this Privacy Policy to ensure that we're complying with all applicable data privacy protections, when required.
What kind of personal data do we collect?
Candidates: To provide personalised employment opportunities, we need to process certain information about you. We only ask for details that are genuinely needed to carry out this task, such as your name, age, contact details, education details, employment history, emergency contacts, immigration status, financial information (where we need to carry out financial background checks), reference information and social security number (and of course you may choose to share other relevant information with us). Where appropriate and in accordance with local laws and requirements, we may also collect information related to your health, diversity information or details of any criminal convictions.
The main reason for using your personal details is to help you find employment or other work roles that might be suitable for you. The more information we have about you, your skillset and your ambitions, the more bespoke we can make our service. Where appropriate and in accordance with local laws and requirements, we may also use your personal data for things like marketing. Where appropriate, we will seek your consent to undertake some of these activities.
Clients: If you are a Snap Care customer, we need to collect and use information about you, or individuals at your organisation, in the course of providing you services such as finding suitable candidates. We only ask for details that are genuinely required to carry out this task, such as your name, contact details, location and the pertinent condition information to find a suitable candidate. The more information we have, the more bespoke we can make our service. We may also use your personal data for things like marketing, our newsletter, for example. Where appropriate, we will seek your consent to undertake some of these activities.
Suppliers: We need a small amount of information from our suppliers to ensure that we can carry out business. We need contact details of relevant individuals at your organisation so that we can communicate with you. We also need other information such as your bank details so that we can pay for the services you provide (if this is part of the contractual arrangements between us).
Other (for example, referees and emergency contacts): In order to provide candidates with suitable employment opportunities safely and securely and to provide for every eventuality for them, we need some basic background information. We only ask for very basic contact details, so that we can get in touch with you either for a reference or because you’ve been listed as an emergency contact for one of our Candidates.
Website and email Users: We collect a limited amount of data from our website and some email users which we use to help us to improve your experience when using our digital services and to help us manage the services we provide. This includes information such as how you use our website, the frequency with which you access our website, the times that our website is most popular and to see if you have read our newsletter.
A number of elements of the personal data we collect from you are required to enable us to fulfil our contractual duties to you or to others. Where appropriate, some, for example Candidates' social security number and, religious affiliation, are required by statute or other laws. Other items may simply be needed to ensure that our relationship can run smoothly.
Depending on the type of personal data in question and the grounds on which we may be processing it, should you decline to provide us with such data, we may not be able to fulfil our contractual requirements or, in extreme cases, may not be able to continue with our relationship.
How do we collect your personal data?
Candidate Data: We collect data directly from you or where you have posted your CV on public job boards.
Client Data: There are two main ways in which we collect your personal data:
Directly from you
From third parties (for example, your case manager)
Supplier Data: We collect your personal data during the course of our work with you.
Other (for example, referees and emergency contacts): We collect your contact details only where a Candidate gives them to us in order for you to serve as a referee.
Website and email Users: We collect your data automatically via cookies when you visit our website, in line with cookie settings in your browser. We automatically collect information when we use our bulk email service for job offers and newsletters to see, for example, if the email has been delivered, opened and if you wish to unsubscribe.
Please note that communications to and from Snap Care' Staff including emails may be reviewed as part of internal or external investigations or litigation.
Who do we share your personal data with?
Candidate Data: We may share your personal data with various parties, in various ways and for various reasons. Primarily we will share your information with prospective employers and associated agents such as case managers and solicitors, to increase your chances of securing the job you want. We may share your personal data with others, such as referees and certifying bodies, to determine Candidate suitability or to meet our legal obligations.
Client Data: We will share your personal data primarily to ensure that we provide you with a suitable pool of Candidates or to meet our legal obligations.
Supplier Data: We will not share your personal data with third parties, other than to meet our legal obligations.
Other (for example, referees and emergency contacts):  We will not share your personal data with third parties, other than to meet our legal obligations.
Website and email Users:  Unless you specify otherwise, we may share your information with providers of web analytics services, marketing automation platforms and social media services to make sure any advertising you receive is targeted to you.
Changes of Business Ownership and Control
Snap Care (part of Snap Childcare Limited) may, expand or reduce its business and this may involve the sale of certain divisions or the transfer of control of certain divisions to other parties. Data provided by users will, where it is relevant to any division so transferred, be transferred along with that division and the new owner or newly controlling party who will, under the terms of this policy, be permitted to use the Data for the purposes for which it was supplied by you.
In the event that any Data submitted by users will be transferred in such a manner, you will be contacted in advance and informed of the changes. When contacted you will be given the choice to have your Data deleted or withheld from the new owner or controller.
How do we safeguard your personal data?
We care about protecting your information. That's why we put in place appropriate measures that are designed to prevent unauthorised access to, and misuse of, your personal data.
How long do we keep your personal data for?
General: If we have not had meaningful contact with you (or, where appropriate, the company you are working for or with) for a period of two years, we will Delete your personal data from our systems unless we believe in good faith that the law or other regulation requires us to preserve it (for example, because of our obligations to tax authorities or in connection with any anticipated litigation).
Legitimate Interest. Where we believe you have an ongoing interest in our service and/or information we send out such as newsletters and updates, we will retain your information.
Individuals we have worked with: We are required to keep your data in relation to child protection, vulnerable adults’ regulations and for our legal recruitment responsibilities.
How can you access, amend or take back the personal data that you have given to us?
Even if we already hold your personal data, you still have various rights in relation to it. To get in touch about these, please contact us. We will seek to deal with your request without undue delay, and in any event in accordance with the requirements of any applicable laws. Please note that we may keep a record of your communications to help us resolve any issues which you raise.
Right to object:
If we are using your data because we deem it necessary for our legitimate interests to do so, and you do not agree, you have the right to object. We will respond to your request within 30 days (although we may be allowed to extend this period in certain cases). Generally, we will only disagree with you if certain limited conditions apply.
Right to withdraw consent: Where we have obtained your consent to process your personal data for certain activities (for example, for profiling your suitability for certain roles), or consent to market to you, you may withdraw your consent at any time.
Data Subject Access Requests: Just so it's clear, you have the right to ask us to confirm what information we hold about you at any time, and you may ask us to modify, update or Delete such information. At this point we may comply with your request or, additionally do one of the following:
- we may ask you to verify your identity, or ask for more information about your request; and
- where we are legally permitted to do so, we may decline your request, but we will explain why if we do so.
Right to erasure: In certain situations (for example, where we have processed your data unlawfully), you have the right to request us to "erase" your personal data. We will respond to your request within 30 days (although we may be allowed to extend this period in certain cases) and will only disagree with you if certain limited conditions apply. If we do agree to your request, we will Delete your data but will generally assume that you would prefer us to keep a note of your name on our register of individuals who would prefer not to be contacted. That way, we will minimise the chances of you being contacted in the future where your data are collected in unconnected circumstances. If you would prefer us not to do this, you are free to say so.
Right of data portability: If you wish, you have the right to transfer your data from us to another data controller. We will help with this – either by directly transferring your data for you, or by providing you with a copy in a commonly used machine-readable format.
Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority: You also have the right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority, details of which can be found here.
If your interests or requirements change, you can unsubscribe from part or all of our marketing content (for example job role emails or Snap Care newsletters) by clicking the unsubscribe link in the email, or by updating your preferences through our preference centre on the Snap Care website (by signing into your account).
Who is responsible for processing your personal data on the Snap Care website?
Snap Care controls the processing of personal data on its website(s).
What are cookies and how do we use them?
A "cookie" is a bite-sized piece of data that is stored on your computer's hard drive. They are used by nearly all websites and do not harm your system. We use them to track your activity to help ensure you get the smoothest possible experience when visiting our website. We can use the information from cookies to ensure we present you with options tailored to your preferences on your next visit. We can also use cookies to analyse traffic and for advertising purposes.
If you want to check or change what types of cookies you accept, this can usually be altered within your browser settings. We also provide information about this in our Marketing preferences page on the Snap Care website.
How to reject cookies
If you don’t want to receive cookies that are not strictly necessary to perform basic features of our site, you may choose to opt-out by changing your browser settings.
Most web browsers will accept cookies but if you would rather we didn’t collect data in this way you can choose to accept all or some, or reject cookies in your browser's privacy settings. However, rejecting all cookies means that you may not be able to take full advantage of all our website's features. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.
If you have questions or comments related to this Privacy Policy, please contact Snap Care 91 -93 Great Eastern Street Shoredicth, London EC2A 3HZ,  020 7729 2200 or info@snapcare.co.uk
Case Managers & Solicitors
Snap Care Brochure
Snap Care Bespoke Recruitment
Snap Recruitment Procedure
The Care Team Package
Snap Shortlist
Snap Job Advert
Recommended Wages
SNAP Care is a trading company of SNAP Childcare Limited, Company Registration 4140483
